export default data = {
  dept: "computerScience",
  courses: "2016 January MOE Computer science department Exit Exam",
  questionCollectionList: [
    {
      year: 2015,
      questionList: [
        {
          question:
            "Which one of the following is concerned with the meaning of a sentence in knowledge representation?",
          op1: "Structure",
          op2: "Computational aspect",
          op3: "Semantics",
          op4: "Syntax",
          answer: "C",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Which one of the following is an attack performed by wiretapping a network and illicitly copy files and programs?",
          op1: "Interception",
          op2: "Fabrication",
          op3: "Interruption",
          op4: "Modification",
          answer: "A",
        },
        {
          question:
            "If a company wants to develop a software for its use, and if the company wants partial functionality to be delivered to end users without unreasonable delay. Which software development process model is appropriate for such requirement?",
          op1: "Waterfall",
          op2: "Incremental",
          op3: "Spiral",
          op4: "Evolutionary",
          answer: "B",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Which one of the following cannot affect proper functioning of a system?",
          op1: "Query graph",
          op2: "Query optimization",
          op3: "Query tree",
          op4: "Query processing",
          answer: "B",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Let KPRIV-A and KPUB-A be private and public keys for Awgichew and KPRIV-M and KPUB-M are private and public keys for Meron respectively. If Awgichew would like to send secured message to Meron, which one of the following scenario is not correct if they are using asymmetric keys?",
          op1: "Awgichew uses Meron’s private key KPRIV-M to encrypt his plain text",
          op2: "Awgichew uses his KPUB-A to encrypt his plain text",
          op3: "Meron can decode the encrypted text using her  KPRIV-M",
          op4: "Meron can decode the scrambled text using her  KPUB-M",
          answer: "B",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Which one of the following agents works by searching and matching the rules defined by percent and stored internal state?",
          op1: "Model-based reflex agent",
          op2: "Goal-based agent",
          op3: "Simple reflex agent",
          op4: "Utility based agent",
          answer: "A",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Which symbol is used to write a single line comment in JavaScript?",
          op1: "<?",
          op2: "<!---------------->",
          op3: "//",
          op4: "&&",
          answer: "C",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Which one of the following is correct about symmetric and asymmetric keys?",
          op1: "Both are authentication methods",
          op2: "Symmetric key requires the sender and receiver to have a public and private key",
          op3: "Asymmetric key requires the sender and receiver to have a public and private key",
          op4: "Both are recovery methods",
          answer: "C",
        },
        {
          question:
            "If you want to test individual sub-systems of software, which phase of software testing is appropriate?",
          op1: "Integration testing",
          op2: "Unit testing",
          op3: "System testing",
          op4: "Acceptance testing",
          answer: "B",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Suppose you are administrating the network. You would like to know list of protocol on use, the foreign address and port numbers, the local address and port number and the state of the connection. Which command would you use to accomplish that?",
          op1: "traceroute",
          op2: "ipconfig",
          op3: "netstart",
          op4: "nslookup",
          answer: "C",
        },
        {
          question:
            "When we use a hash table data structure, our hash function should map the expected inputs (keys) as evenly as possible over its output range(indexes). This property of good hash function is known as______.",
          op1: "Uniformity",
          op2: "Determinism",
          op3: "Continuity",
          op4: "Data normalization",
          answer: "A",
        },
        {
          question:
            "In an array implementation of binary heap tree, if a node is stored as index i, then its right child will be stored as index_______",
          op1: "2*i+1",
          op2: "i/2",
          op3: "(i+1)/2",
          op4: "2*i",
          answer: "A",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Which one of the following is false about sequential and binary searching algorithm?",
          op1: "Binary searching algorithm can work on list of data which is stored in descending order",
          op2: "Sequential and binary searching algorithm are not equal in terms of memory efficiency",
          op3: "Sequential searching algorithm can work on sorted and unsorted list of data",
          op4: "Considering worst case analysis binary searching algorithm is faster than sequential searching on sorted data.",
          answer: "C",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Which of the following term refers to the number of symbols composing a string?",
          op1: "Length",
          op2: "Symbols",
          op3: "Alphabet",
          op4: "Word",
          answer: "C",
        },
        {
          question:
            "________ is a way of combining analogue or digital signals into one single over a common or shared medium",
          op1: "Point-to-point",
          op2: "Broadcasting",
          op3: "Synchronization ",
          op4: "Multicasting",
          answer: "D",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Which generation’s programming languages are used in Artificial intelligence and Expert systems?",
          op1: "Fifth generation languages",
          op2: "Second generation languages",
          op3: "Fourth generation languages",
          op4: "Third generation languages",
          answer: "A",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Which attribute of INPUT tag defines the number of characters that can be displayed in a text box without scrolling?",
          op1: "SIZE",
          op2: "MAXLENGTH",
          op3: "VALUE",
          op4: "TYPE",
          answer: "B",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Which characteristics of requirement specify that the requirements should be phrased so that there is one and only one interpretation for it?",
          op1: "Correct",
          op2: "Unambiguous",
          op3: "Feasible",
          op4: "Verifiable",
          answer: "B",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Which method can be used to divide a browser into smaller sub windows so that each sub window displaying a different HTML document?",
          op1: "Using paragraphs",
          op2: "Using frames",
          op3: "Using images",
          op4: "Using tables",
          answer: "B",
        },
      ],
    },
  ],
};
